CV - Sagiv Malihi

CONTACT Information King David Ave. 23, Tel-Aviv phone: (+972)-52-6087182 email: sagivmalihi@gmail.com

Summary

Experienced R&D leader, hacking my way through software systems since age 8. My current religions - javascript (not python), vim (not emacs) and spaces (not tabs), though these have changed multiple times over the past 30 years. Building software is great, building an excellent R&D organization that builds great software is even better. Currently interested in AI, humans, and how to best mix the two.

Professional Experience

Aleph EIR

2020 - Present

Aleph is a leading Israeli early stage VC

Heat Intelligence Co-Founder and CTO

2016 - 2020

Cloud service for intelligence on demand, providing cognitive services in real time by a hybrid cloud of humans and AI. Bootstrapped to \sim \$1m ARR. Service is stil live.

Intucell (acquired by Cisco) R&D Group Manager

2011 - 2016

Led a group (\sim 40 engineers) developing a highly scalable, fault tolerant system for cellular networks radio optimization (on-prem cluster of \sim 200 servers, pre-kubernetes)

XIV (acquired by IBM) Software Developer

2009 - 2011

Klapka.co.il Co-Founder

2008 - 2009

Localized version of Threadless.com, nice side-project

IDF (8200) Information Security Research

2001 - 2009

Various infosec roles ranging from mathematical research through HPC, to low-level / embedded systems security research

EDUCATION

Hebrew University, Jerusalem, Israel

2005 - 2008

B.Sc., Mathematics

"Haman Talpiot - Aham" Course, IDF

2000 - 2001

Galili High School, Kfar-Saba, Israel

1997 - 2000